Yuri!
侑里小姐！
Tae-o?
泰晤？
Yes?
什麼？
I'm okay.
我沒事
Are you okay, Yuri?
侑里小姐還好嗎？
I'm okay. Are you hurt anywhere?
我沒事，你有沒有受傷？
I'm okay.
我安然無恙
I knew it. It's my fault.
果然會這樣，都是我的錯
It's my fault. I'm really sorry, Tae-o.
是我不好，泰晤，對不起…
It's fine.
別介意
It's not your fault, Yuri.
這不是侑里小姐的錯
See?
你看
I'm completely fine.
完全沒問題
Thank you.
謝謝你
Let's go. I'll walk you home.
回去吧，我送你一程
I insist.
不行
I'll walk you home.
我送你回去
I won't leave you.
我堅持要這麼做
You're a scaredy-cat, aren't you?
侑里小姐真膽小
I like that about you.
我也喜歡你這一點
That's a flaw.
那是缺點啦
A flaw?
缺點？
Yeah, it's a bad thing about me.
對，就是不好的地方
What?
什麼？
Are there any bad things about you?
侑里小姐身上有不好的地方嗎？
There are a lot.
有很多喔
Oh, by chance, do you mean how your face gets scary
是喔，像是表情很可怕
and such?
這一點算嗎？
That's only when I get hungry, right?
我很餓的時候才會那樣吧？
Hmm, who knows?
嗯，這可難說喔
Anything else?
還有別的嗎？
Well…
我想想…
It's also not good how you treat me
你總是把我當成小狗對待
like a dog.
這一點也不太好喔
I'm sorry.
真不好意思
Oh, right.
對了
Your sea otter drawings are bad.
海獺的插圖畫得很差
Why was your sea otter…
你畫的海獺為什麼…
able to stand?
都是站直的樣子呢？
Throw that note away. It's embarrassing.
那紙條讓我好害羞，你就丟掉吧
I like everything about you, Yuri.
我喜歡侑里小姐的全部
Everything.
你的所有一切
I loved it all.
都曾讓我深深著迷
Yes. Thank you.
嗯，謝謝你
Oh, um, sorry about that.
啊，那個，對不起喔
Goodbye then.
那我走了
Take care.
你要保重喔
-Good morning.
-早安
-Here's the package. -Thank you.
-機車快遞來了，有貴公司的信 -謝謝
This is bad, Boss!
大事不好啦，社長！
It's from Tae-o!
這是泰晤寄來的…
What's wrong?
怎麼了嗎？
RESIGNATION LETTER
（辭呈）
Huh? Why did he resign?
不會吧？這是怎麼回事？
Did I accidentally bully him at work?
難道是我不小心對他職權騷擾了嗎？
I got my divorce papers like this too.
當年咱的離婚協議書也是這樣寄來的
What a nightmare.
簡直是惡夢哪
We'll look into this, so please go back to work, everyone.
我這邊會再做確認，請大家照常上班
AUDIO CALL
（語音通話）
Yuri and I…
我和侑里小姐…
broke up.
分手了
I see.
這樣啊
What about work?
那公司呢？
Would you like to return to the lab?
如果不介意，要不要回來研究室？
No.
不
I'm going back to Seoul.
我要回首爾了
What?
什麼？
Yuri…
侑里小姐…
learned about how the picture book ends.
已經知道繪本的結局了
If…
如果…
something happened to me again…
我又出了什麼事
Yuri…
侑里小姐…
would blame herself.
一定會很自責
If that will keep you safe,
如果那樣做能保護你的安全
I won't stop you.
我不會阻止你
Tae-o.
泰晤
There are people out there praying for your safety.
有人會為你祈求平安
Please keep that in mind.
唯獨這件事，請你要記得
Yuri too…
侑里小姐她…
She's surely…
一定也是…
Thank you.
謝謝
Time to eat.
我開動了
Delicious food is the best way to get energized.
吃美味的料理是最棒的能量補給
That's why I always make sure to eat on both good and bad days.
所以我啊
Enjoy.
請享用吧
We finished the chocolate shaved ice recipe
夏季快閃店要推出的巧克力刨冰
for this summer's pop-up shop.
食譜已經完成了
Can you choose a container and price that matches it
麻煩你們挑選容器，制定售價
and proofread the press release?
然後還要檢查新聞稿
-Yes. -Aihara, please proceed with the schedule.
-好的 -相原，請照這個排程推動
She sure is working hard.
瞧她拚成這樣
I wonder why things aren't going well for her.
為什麼會不順利呢？
Because of the power she's had until now,
侑里小姐至今因為擁有那能力
she's gone through so much.
應該吃了不少苦頭
Now, she's even lost Tae-o.
現在居然連泰晤也走了
-Please finish it quickly if you can. -Okay.
-希望你這邊的進度可以快一點 -好的
But I'm sure this company,
可是不管是公司
including us,
還是我們
were protected time and time again by Motomiya's power.
一定也被本宮她的能力 幫了很多次才對
You might be right.
或許是沒錯啦
However, even if she has broken up with Tae-o,
可是就算和泰晤分手了
having that power
只要侑里小姐還有那種能力
means that she can never fall in love with anyone.
不就表示她不能再喜歡上任何人嗎？
That's too painful.
那太讓人難受了
-By the way, Hanaoka… -Yeah?
-對了，花岡先生 -嗯？
You remember what today is, right?
你應該沒忘記今天是什麼日子吧？
Of course I haven't.
我怎麼可能會忘
You've definitely forgotten.
我看你一定是忘了
I'm so glad the three of us get to celebrate again this year.
太好了，今年又能三個人一起慶祝
-Here's this year's cake. -Whoa.
-來，是今年的蛋糕 -天啊
-Ta-da! It's coffee-flavored. -Wow, looks delicious.
-請看，是咖啡口味喔 -好棒，感覺真好吃
Our chocolatier is so talented.
不愧是我們的巧克力師傅
Just so you know, it's the best cake in the world.
我先聲明，這可是全世界最美味的喔
Well, let's have a toast.
那就正式來吧
To celebrate Dolce &amp; Chocolat. and its ninth year…
祝朵契與巧克力創業九周年…
-Cheers. -Cheers!
-乾杯 -乾杯！
Congratulations.
恭喜
Let's eat.
我開動了
-Let's eat.
-開動了
This is so good!
真美味！
You're amazing, Mahiro.
我好佩服你喔，真尋
Right?
是吧？
-It's great. -I'm glad.
-好吃 -太好了
It's so good!
好吃耶！
-Hey. -Yuri.
-我說啊… -侑里小姐…
Um…
那個…
Do you want to try that thing with Tae-o?
你要不要和泰晤試試看那個？
Huh?
什麼？
From the picture book.
繪本裡不是有寫
Getting rid of your power.
消除那能力的方法嗎？
Oh, that.
哦，那個啊
I tried it with my Dad, but my power didn't go away.
我和父親試過了，可是能力沒有消失
Oh, really?
哦，這樣啊？
So, that was the only fictional part of that book?
那就表示繪本 那部分的內容是杜撰的？
But if you get rid of your power, you and Tae-o can be together.
但是只要讓能力消失 本宮和泰晤就能在一起了
It's okay.
你放心
Hanaoka and I will look after your happiness no matter what.
我和花岡先生不管用什麼方法 都會守護好侑里小姐的幸福
What? Me too?
什麼？我也要？
Of course.
當然啊
How long have we been in this together, huh?
我們都認識幾年了？
It's your job to protect Motomiya, isn't it?
保護本宮，這不就是你的職責嗎？
Yes.
是的
Thanks.
謝謝你們
Keep eating.
多吃點
This is good.
非常好吃
That's great.
那就好
FROM MIN HA-NA DEAR MR. HANAOKA
（花岡先生你好 我是閔荷娜）
Hello?
你好
Sorry for calling at this late hour. This is Hanaoka.
抱歉這麼晚還致電打擾 我是朵契與巧克力的花岡
I'm sorry to bother you, but I wanted to ask you something.
恕我冒昧，但我有一個問題想請教
It's about the picture book.
是關於那繪本
Is it true that you lose your power if you lock eyes for 33 seconds?
請問兩人對視33秒能力就會消失 這段描述是真的嗎？
That was…
其實…
what I hoped for.
那只是個希望
Hope?
希望？
At the time,
當時啊
soon after I lost him,
在我的男友過世後不久
I had the chance to go to Hokkaido.
我有機會去北海道
When I was there, I read an old Ainu legend.
在當地我讀到了一個 阿伊努族的古老傳說
In that legend,
在傳說中
there was a method for getting rid of a similar power.
寫著能消除類似能力的方法
I wasn't able to test it.
可惜我已經無法嘗試了
That's why I put it in the picture book…
所以我才會將其寄託在繪本中
Hope.
寄託希望
I HAVE A QUESTION. YOU STUDY ANIMALS FROM HOKKAIDO, RIGHT?
（我記得你們有在研究 北海道的動物吧？）
Excuse me.
打擾了
The chocolatier?
巧克力師傅？
Mahiro?
真尋小姐？
Why are you here?
你為什麼會來？
There's something I'd like to ask you two.
我有件事情想請教兩位
I see. An Ainu legend.
原來如此，是阿伊努族的傳說啊
So, you do know it?
你果然知道嗎？
Yes, though I'm not an expert,
是的，雖然這不是我的專業
I looked into Ainu narratives long ago
但我常為了研究蝦夷鳴兔而去北海道
out of curiosity on one of my many research trips to Hokkaido
有機會接觸阿伊努族的民間故事
where I studied the northern pika.
我曾經出於好奇調查過
Wow, that's perfect.
就是那個，太棒了
I think I have the book too.
我記得有文獻
What?
什麼？
I think it was around here.
我記得好像放在這裡
Not here.
不過這邊好像沒有呢
Oh, here it is.
啊，就是這箱
Found it.
找到了
Yes, the ohainu.
對了，就是“ohainu”
This Ainu legend tells of someone who saves humans and animals
在阿伊努族傳說中 有個人曾經被神明救回一命
after hearing the voice of a god who once saved their life.
之後那個人類就聽到神明的聲音 去幫助其他人和動物
This is it.
就是這個沒錯
I never made the connection before.
的確，當時我並沒有發現
It's like the picture book.
這確實很像那繪本的內容
Oh, here it is. 33 seconds.
哦，就是這段，“33秒”
But this method doesn't get rid of it.
可是她說這方法不能消除能力
Isn't there anything else?
還有其他的嗎？應該有吧？
Sorry, but this isn't my area of expertise--
不好意思，我畢竟不是專業的…
I'm sure there must be a way.
還有其他的吧？一定會有的
Please come up with something.
就算是硬要想也要想出來
Ms. Chocolatier, please calm down.
等等，這位巧克力師傅，請你冷靜
Are you really giving up here? Aren't researchers supposed to be smart?
你要放棄了？既然是在做研究的 腦袋應該很聰明吧？
Please use that brain to think of a way.
請用你的腦袋想想辦法啊
-Um, I-- -How about this?
-那個，我… -還有這一份
What is that?
那是什麼？
Documents about the Ainu language. The professor asked me to decipher them.
是阿伊努語的資料 當時教授拜託我解讀
But I was too lazy and hid them.
不過我嫌麻煩，就把它藏起來了
Is it a spell? What does it say?
是咒語？寫著什麼？
I'm not sure. I'm not an expert either.
不曉得，我也不是專攻這塊的
It doesn't matter if you are or not.
不管是不是專攻的都好
Decipher it right now.
拜託你現在就開始解讀
Those are important papers. Wait, I'll take those for now.
這份資料很重要，我先保管…
I'll do it, okay?
好啦，我做就是了
Hello? What is it, Mahiro?
喂？真尋，怎麼了？
Yuri, you do it under the stars!
侑里小姐，要在星空下！
What?
什麼？
Like I said, under the stars!
我說要在星空下！
We haven't deciphered everything yet.
我們還沒有完全解讀出來
And we're still debating it.
而且還有很多種假設
You need to lock eyes with the one you love under the stars for 33 seconds.
要在星空下和相愛的人對視33秒
You can get rid of that power!
你的能力是可以消除的！
My dear doctor, I'm so impressed. I'm seeing you in a new light.
真不愧是我的博士，對你刮目相看了
You saw me in a bad light before?
原來你之前對我的評價那麼低？
I mean, you never said what I wanted to hear.
誰叫你從來沒對我說過…
What is that?
說什麼？
It's nothing.
沒事啦
As of now, on this very planet,
目前在這地球上
they say there are millions of diverse species.
據說一共有數千萬種多樣的生物
Wow.
是喔
Of those millions of species, we are from the exact same species.
我們只是數千萬種中的一種 是同一個物種
That's true.
是啊
However, our genes are all different.
但是我們的基因不同
Out of all the humans in our species,
你在人類這物種之中
your genes draw me in the most.
擁有最吸引我的基因
So, what does that mean?
所以說，你的意思是？
Basically, what's important here…
簡單來說，重點是…
The thing that attracts me…
能夠吸引我的人…
is you alone, on this entire planet.
在這地球上只有你一個
That's what I mean.
這就是我想說的
What's the matter?
你在做什麼？
Oh, is this a smooch?
難道是接吻行為嗎？
Your word choice gives me the creeps.
你的用詞好噁心喔
I guess that's fine though.
我是無所謂啦
I'm the one who fell in love with you fully knowing that was the case.
誰叫我明明知道你是那種人 卻還是喜歡上你
Me too.
我也是
You…
你也是？
What?
什麼意思？
I…
我…
love you too.
也喜歡真尋小姐
You finally said it.
你終於對我說了
HARMONY CARE CENTER
（和諧照護中心）
I see.
這樣啊
Well done on your decision.
你做出決定了啊，真是勇敢
Hey, Yuri.
聽我說，侑里
Life has its bitter days and its sweet ones.
人生中會有苦澀的一天 也會有甜蜜的一天
That's because we face our feelings head-on during our lives.
那就是你勇於面對自身內心 不停努力活著的證明
Simply follow the path that you want to take.
你誠實往想走的路前進就行
You don't have to hide your own feelings from yourself.
唯獨對自己，是不需要隱瞞真心的
I'm…
我啊…
glad I'm your dad.
果然很慶幸能當你的爸爸
Dad…
爸爸…
Yuri.
侑里
Hold my hands.
來握握看我的手吧
Thank you, Dad.
謝謝你，爸爸
Tae-o.
泰晤
Yes?
嗯？
Sorry to call you here.
抱歉把你叫出來
It's fine.
別介意
Um, what brings you to Seoul?
請問你怎麼會特地來首爾？
A contract with Ms. Min.
我是來和閔小姐簽合約的
I see.
這樣啊
Also…
還有…
This.
這一封
I can't take this without a signature.
你沒簽名，我們沒辦法受理
Oh, I'm sorry.
啊，不好意思
What a nice place.
這裡真是個好地方
Why did you come here without a word?
你怎麼不跟大家說一聲 就突然回首爾？
Because I can't stay
因為我不能待在
by Yuri's side.
侑里小姐身邊
Did you know?
你知道嗎？
They say that if we consider our thoughts to be 100%,
假設人在腦中想的事情有100%這麼多
the amount conveyed to the listener
但能用言語傳達給對方的
is actually only 5%.
聽說其實只有5%左右
Only 5%?
只有5%？
So, wouldn't that 5%
既然這樣，那這5%…
be a waste if we don't treasure it?
不在重要時刻用，不就浪費了嗎？
What is this?
這是什麼？
ITINERARY
（機票行程單）
You're still considered our employee.
泰晤，你還勉強算是我們的員工
Consider this
這就當作是我給你的業務命令
I'm abusing my power just this once.
偶爾可以讓我濫用一下職權吧
Yuri?
侑里小姐？
Tae-o.
泰晤
I missed you.
我好想你
I missed your voice.
好想聽你的聲音
I missed your face. I missed you.
好想看你的臉，真的很想念你
Me too.
我也是
Can I tell you something?
泰晤，你願意聽我說嗎？
Yes.
好
I, um…
我其實…
I…
我…
can hear…
聽得到…
your thoughts, Tae-o.
泰晤內心的聲音
I heard them this whole time.
我一直都聽得到
But I couldn't tell you.
可是我說不出口
I was always too scared.
我總是很害怕
Yuri, you're…
侑里小姐，你啊…
such a scaredy-cat.
真是膽小呢
I like you, Tae-o.
我喜歡你，泰晤
I love you.
最喜歡你了
I want to always be with you.
我想和你永遠在一起
I don't want to be away from you anymore.
不想再和你分開
Me too.
我也是
I love you.
我喜歡侑里小姐
But…
可是…
I don't want you to suffer.
我不想看到侑里小姐難過
Those are both how I truly feel.
兩邊都是我的真心話
I'm so relieved.
太好了
It's so pretty.
真漂亮
Yeah.
是啊
Let's begin then.
那我們就開始吧
Okay.
好
Tae-o.
泰晤
I want to know how you felt back then.
我想知道泰晤那時候的感覺
When?
那時候？
When we first met,
我們第一次見面的時候
what were you thinking?
你在想什麼？
-Are you mad? -I’m not mad.
-你在生氣嗎？ -我沒有在生氣
She's really mad…
她超級生氣的
Your face was really scary back then.
你那時的表情真的好可怕
Sorry.
對不起
It's okay. I'm sure we'll meet again.
沒關係，我們一定會再見面
But I wish we could stay together a bit longer.
可是我想和你再多相處一下
Do you like me?
你喜歡我嗎？
But that's the Yuri I fell in love with.
可是我喜歡上了那樣的你
Every day, no matter when it may be,
每一天、不管是什麼時候
I love you.
我都喜歡著侑里小姐
If Yuri is someone who helps others,
如果侑里小姐想幫助別人
I want to be the one to help her.
那我希望能幫助她
That was a lie.
我說謊了
I'm sorry.
對不起
To be honest, I really love you a lot.
其實我非常愛你
I really want to enjoy this time
我想要好好享受
that I'm spending with you right now.
和你在一起的這段時光
I liked you, just the way you are.
我就是喜歡你現在這樣子
No, I don't want this.
我果然還是不想這樣
Why?
為什麼？
Don't get rid of it.
請你不要消除能力
The one I fell in love with
我所愛上的
is you, the Yuri you've always been.
就是現在的侑里小姐
I want to stay with you forever, Yuri,
我想和最真實的侑里小姐一直在一起
just the way you are.
直到永遠
I…
我…
can't hear your thoughts.
雖然聽不到心聲
But I still understand your feelings.
但是我能明白侑里小姐的心情
I may not understand all of them,
我或許不能明白全部
but I want to know…
可是我想深入…
your feelings…
了解…
As much as I can.
你的內心
It's okay.
放心吧
We will…
我們兩人啊
get through this.
一定可以克服
Tae-o.
泰晤
I love you.
我愛你
Me too.
我也是
ON LEAVE WITH YURI. KYOSHUKU DESU. TAE-O.
（我和侑里小姐請帶薪假 真是過意不去，泰晤）
-Aihara. -Yes?
-相原 -是
The year for the intern job posting is wrong.
招募實習生的年度不對
Why would we hire interns for last year?
你招募去年的實習生要做什麼？
What? I'm sorry.
什麼？不好意思
Nishina, my daughter got a boyfriend,
仁科小姐，咱女兒交到男朋友了
and we're all eating together for the first time today.
咱今天要和他們第一次去吃飯
So you got a haircut?
所以你才剪那髮型？
Yeah, how is it?
是啊，覺得怎樣？
I can't even answer that.
不怎麼樣耶
You should let go of the cut.
我衷心勸你不要
What? But I can't change it back now.
什麼？已經改不回去了哪
MIN HA-NA NEXT YEAR'S BUSINESS PLANS
（閔荷娜 關於明年的業務計劃）
The reason why your boyfriend died was coronary artery disease.
你男友的死因是缺血性心臟病
Even before he met you, he was suffering from heart issues.
他在和你相遇以前就已患有心臟疾病
His death…
我想他會過世…
was not because of your power.
並不是因為那能力害的
Nor was it your fault.
也不是因為你造成的
DEAR MR. HANAOKA, THIS IS MIN FROM KJH.
（花岡先生你好，我是KJH的閔）
THE SAKURA ARE IN FULL BLOOM IN JAPAN. AFTER OUR MEETING…
（日本正值櫻花盛開的季節 開完會後）
WOULD YOU LIKE TO COME SEE THEM WITH OUR TEAM?
（要不要與敝公司員工 一起去賞個花呢？）
Hold on a second. I'm so tired.
等一下，我好累
You're too slow.
你走好慢喔
Your legs are longer than mine.
我們的腿長又不一樣
That again?
又是那句？
Hey, I'm hungry.
我好餓喔
-Are you mad? -I am.
-你生氣了嗎？ -我很生氣
When people fall in love,
人只要喜歡上另一個人
they wish to know their partner's thoughts.
就會希望能得知對方的真心話
Yuri, open wide.
侑里小姐，張嘴
However, it's impossible to look into someone's heart
但是人的內心沒有任何人能窺探
or to completely understand each other.
也不可能理解彼此的一切
-Is it good? -It's good.
-好吃嗎？ -好吃
-Get energized.
-能量補給
Oh, it's a shooting star.
哦，有流星
Hm? Where?
什麼？哪裡？
Look, it's over there.
你看，就在那裡…
Hm?
有嗎？
-Yuri. -Yeah?
-侑里小姐 -嗯？
A present.
送你的禮物
Glass.
玻璃戒指
A sea otter color.
還是海獺色的
It's pretty.
好漂亮
For me?
我可以收下嗎？
Yeah.
可以
-Here? -Huh?
-戴這裡？ -嗯？
-Or here? -Hm?
-還是這裡？
But that's okay.
不過那樣就好
Because if you understand…
就算只有一點點…
Thank you.
謝謝你
…each other's hearts, even just a tiny bit…
只要能明白彼此的真心
I think
我認為…
that's a miracle.
那就已經是奇蹟了
Wow, it's so pretty. I'm glad we came.
好漂亮喔，來這裡真是選對了
Do you like the ocean?
你喜歡海嗎？
You do, right?
你很喜歡吧？
He does love it, but he wants to hurry to the hot springs.
他說他喜歡海沒錯 不過現在更想快點泡溫泉
Okay, let's go.
知道了，我們走吧
Let's go.
走吧
Oh, did you enjoy your hot spring trip?
對了，上次溫泉旅行還愉快嗎？
Bravo.
好極了
May I join you next time? How about Kusatsu?
下次我也可以一起去嗎？ 去草津如何？
Okay, got it.
了解，我知道了
Um, there's something inside the tank.
那個，水槽裡有東西耶
No need to worry.
不必擔心
That case and ring are titanium, which is highly resistant to rusting from water.
外盒和戒指都是碰了水 也不易生鏽的鈦合金製的
We can keep it on during work,
工作時不需要特地拿下來
and no eight-barbel loaches were harmed--
對斑北鰍也不會造成壞影響…
Did you do research
你特地研究了嗎？
on how to give a romantic proposal for me?
研究會讓我心動的求婚方法？
I spent 773 hours on it.
大約花了我773小時
-I love you, Darling! -Whoa, wait.
-我最喜歡你了，親愛的！ -天啊，等一下
-Oh, right. -Hm?
-對了 -什麼？
That over there
你看到的那棟就是
is the house I grew up in.
我出生的家
Oh, really?
真的嗎？
Which one?
哪一棟？
That one.
那一棟
-That one? -That one.
-那一棟嗎？ -是那一棟
-Oh, the blue one? -No.
-哦，那間藍色屋頂的？ -不是
The one above it, with the red roof.
上面那間紅色屋頂的
Red?
紅色？
That one?
是那棟啊？
That's right.
沒錯
You were born here, huh?
原來泰晤是在這裡出生的啊？
You want to know more about me, right?
你想更了解我，對不對？
Yeah.
對
Why?
為什麼？
Because I like you.
因為我喜歡你
I love you, Yuri.
我愛你，侑里小姐
Tae-o.
泰晤
I love you.
我愛你
That's not fair.
不公平啦
I can't hear yours.
我又聽不到
Oh, that's right.
啊，對了
How about we yell our wishes?
我們大聲許個願好嗎？
-Our wishes? -Yes.
-許願？ -對
Okay.
好
I like Yuri.
我喜歡侑里小姐
I love her!
最喜歡她了！
Is that a wish?
那算願望嗎？
-Yes. -Oh?
-對 -是喔
I like you too!
我也喜歡你！
I like you, Tae-o!
我喜歡泰晤！
Yuri!
侑里小姐！
I love you!
我愛你！
I really, really love you!
我好愛你！